[Music]
plus we have some amazing set of
stalwart speakers let me go ahead
quickly and invite and introduce them
for all of you
we have it as uh mr anil kesha who's the
chief executive officer
bank nepal we're also joined by sunita
honda who's a cgm
i.t channels and ops global i.t center
with state bank of
india we're also joined by nitin agarwal
president
group cio with edelweiss group we also
have with us aaron lee who's a chief
information officer united asia finance
we also have with us mr vikas survey
who's the co-founder
of vda info solutions mr garish nayak
chief service operations and technology
icici bombard
and satyan jambu nathan chief financial
officer
icic prudential life insurance now we
also have with us that one person who's
responsible
in extracting perspectives from all our
amazing speakers we're joined by
nimilita chatterjee
partner financial services risk
analytics business consulting with evi
india so warm welcome indeed to all of
our fabulous speakers thank you so much
for joining us this morning and with
that i'd like to hand over the
proceedings to nimilita
over to you thank you
thank you thank you so much kavya
is indeed a pleasure to be here this
morning and
um it is you know there's one word and
you sum it up very very beautifully when
you said really there's one word that
sums this entire
the situation that we've been in for the
lack of a better word
uh from march onwards it's really been
one thing after another
um and i think everybody is thinking
about the fact that
with 2020 going away probably all of
these problems will go away but i don't
all of us i guess around the table know
that with the turn of the year nothing
really happens
you know the 1st of january is just like
31st of december
nothing much is going to happen unless
of course in all these talks of things
like vaccine and all of that
uh start becoming a reality well having
said that
given that given the situation that we
are all in
and probably for the lack of a better
word we are calling it
a crisis uh although i don't know if in
bfsi really we could refer to it as a
crisis i think
uh the crisis in some way or the other
has broken us
out of many types of slumber that we
were in
probably you know in the past few years
or
the slowness that maybe had crept in in
some of us
has really gone away so what i'll do is
really
uh for the st panel first of all we have
a large panel and we have only about
50 odd minutes so i'd please request you
to keep your comments
as as quick as possible uh but what i'll
do to start off
is really walk go around the table for
the first time
and really see what has that what is it
one thing that the crisis really changed
uh
in your lives professionally in your
professional lives
and i'll start with mr shah uh if it
would be really nice to hear that
one thing you know that that really
changed uh from march to where we are
now
uh i think that one thing uh has to be
mindset in
our case maybe most of our cases because
the mindset in the past was very
different from the mindset we find
ourselves in today
um all of us had drps bcps so on and so
forth but all of them nepal being in a
seismic zone
if there is an earthquake if there's a
fire so on and so forth none of that
happened we were prepared for it
our infrastructure is solid and working
perfectly fine
but we the humans couldn't get to it so
we had to change the mindset in the way
we work
in the way we deal with customers in the
way we look at risk as well as the way
we look at opportunities
because this is also brought about a lot
of opportunities we only talk about the
downside
there's also been an upside to this but
the mindset has had
gone through a paradigm shift i think
from from the time
we had the first positive in the
parliament to where we are today
and and that i think is the biggest
thing that has changed uh
in this duration for us absolutely right
never let a crisis go waste right i
guess that's what that's what we're all
all thinking about uh miss honda uh over
to you
i what is that one thing if you could
quickly tell us
yeah i'll say one thing but in three
parts very briefly
see first thing is our fast responder
mindset
came to test it was tested absolutely
reacting to the situation responding
without any delay
immediately because sbi had to serve the
nation the government
the new schemes and you know 48 crore
customers a
b is bcp is was no longer
the solution we had to have bccp
business continuity and change planning
that replaced the usual bcp we had
and third is we all have decided to not
let the crisis go waste
there there have been learnings
regarding work from anywhere it works
digital customers have learned oh
digital is easy
so this is the third part this is the
learning relearning
and we are going to go ahead with many
things which we
had you know adopted just to tide over
the crisis
thank you thank you thank you that
that's again very
that's very pertinent mr agarwal coming
to you
um if you could have if we could have
your comments please
for me the biggest change has been um
you know around
customer and internal behavior i think
we've all talked about digital
transformation how much time
will it take what will be the time to
adopt for customers
and i think repeatedly it has shown
whether you talk about
upi framework which government of india
launch or
gst framework which we launched or a
covet crisis where
organizations irrespective of their
vintage and
um you know caliber had to go through
anthology was able to adopt how quickly
people were
able to adopt when the resolution came
to the forefront that there was no
choices given
[Music]
um i think is the biggest testament to
the fact that
you know technology can play a very very
very big role
i think it's the mindsets of the people
which always
are constraining in terms of evolution
of
ourselves the technology and what we can
achieve
but when there is a crisis i think the
world is already
full with technology and support systems
and infrastructure
it's us who have to think differently i
have always believed that customers
adopt much faster than the enterprises
this crisis has again shown us that um
you know customers quickly switched to
e-commerce platforms digital platforms
we did not have to do you know the
training programs for
them you know historically enterprise
systems rollout itself are one year
exercise with training programs
customers don't need the training
programs how you design the system which
are self-resilient
so it has taught us a lot of things and
i i'm hoping
the industry that
internalized and this is around how we
do application delivery how we do
security delivery what is the mindset on
security right i mean we were all into
perimeter mindset and we talked about it
how remote taxes was not allowed and
stuff like that and we've
we've quickly moved there so
i think that technology footprint is
already there
i think it's our resolve to quickly
change that and adopt is
this is great thank you very much
uh mr lee uh from you please
actually because uh coffee 19 the first
happened phase
is in china and then uh my company
is the one of the major finance company
in really china region we are provide
kind of banking service and money
landing service
to our many cities in china
and hong kong and you know the covet 19
totally we are changing
uh so much particularly using disruptive
technologies
to help our customers to engage with us
because
uh in hong kong particularly in hong
kong
uh because we lock down for a long while
and then uh the people
is not allowed to go to our branches
just like uh the normal banking service
we can't go to
uh doing some normal application even
submit the form
in uh some uh banking service inquiry
something like that
we can't do this and then we are totally
changed uh
using online channel to engage with our
customer
and then uh because of all kinds of
social behavior we can use
ai captured by our social listening
solution
and then consolidate all kind of
customer data
with uh the social listening data
together and then project
uh the customer behavior how impact to
our organization
uh this nine month is uh a
uh to hong kong and china it's a
a very uh surplus years to us because
we change our what happened uh we have a
new normal
uh scenario in hong kong and great china
region
you know uh we are we are the first
phase
can control kopi 19 particularly in
china
and taiwan and hong kong so now uh
the government pandemic situation in
china and hong kong
is competitively is so stable but
our revenue in terms of our company
revenue
we increase uh exponentially so compared
with
uh the other country like a western
country
like in us the situation is not like
that
so uh the new number is a big shift fund
uh normally it's a western uh country or
u.s canada now uh the major changes
go to our asia and particularly in buda
china region
so i i think this kind of significant
changes
will continue in the coming three years
so
this is uh so uh in hong kong we have
many
uh university research particularly for
uh the next
generation of customer behavior we do
very uh in depth on that we will
leverage most of ai blockchain
cloud computing big data okay we can say
this is abcd abcd technologies
to make new way of work new way of
engagement with our customer
thanks my sharing thank you thank you mr
lee i think again
um great perspectives mr savi uh your
views please uh
well i can see a major change in our own
customers mind
and that is because of their customers
mindset change
you have seen the digital payment which
has been accepted across
india quite widely now uh same thing has
happened if you see with ekyc and other
things which were
earlier not possible and work from home
become a new normal which
many of the fintech was earlier
objecting to so this is a big change and
this is change has brought up a
new uh thanks to our business also
great great uh mr nayak please
yeah uh you know other panelists have
talked about uh how but this changes
affected the customer and
uh the employees i'll just talk about uh
the way
uh it's affected our industry especially
general insurance
we are industry which has been typically
while you have customers approaching us
digitally but it's still largely
physical interactions physical
infrastructure and uh
done through a large distribution
network whether it's agents dealers or
brokers now what uh the
whole shift to technology and digital
has helped is that
the adoption of all the solutions that
we had for our distribution
has been uh
sped up exponentially i mean we had uh
solutions in place for a long time for
uh digital issues of policies for
uh digital claims surveys digital
servicing
but the adoption by the channels was
not as we would have liked it
visiting the branch or having our
surveyors visit their
garages because of the
whole lockdown and the social distancing
uh put in by the uh
pandemic then suddenly digital became
the only way they could operate and they
could see how
easy it was to get their work done
through the digital solutions that we
offer them so that's
the adoption really has uh in the
distribution
uh has really uh gone up exponentially
great great so i think everything is
changing right whether it is the
customer whether it's a distribution
channel all of that
mr jambo nothing your final views and
then we can move to the main questions
please
thanks nimilita if i were to summarize
in a brief way i would say
need for resilience in line with the
theme that we are talking about
and i'll pick on from what giri spoke
about in the insurance industry we are
probably
tuned to thinking of probabilities we
are tuned to thinking of extreme events
but you do realize that situations like
these
that no amount of tuning on probability
or tuning of thinking on extreme events
quite prepares you for the consequences
that practically emerge
and therefore of course there is the one
part of preparation
there is also the other part of how do
you
build the entire ecosystem to be
resilient to deal with the various
stakeholders
and i think girish beautifully described
the stakeholders as well
we have the consumers and the customers
in their own service behavior
we have the distributors in their own
prospecting
and fulfillment behavior we have
employees in their own way of working in
a day-to-day
environment and we also have a situation
where some of the physical processes you
would have to execute
in your business as usual are not
possible anymore
and therefore you start using the
ecosystem
as a key enabler to deliver process
as far as fulfillment or servicing is
concerned
so to my mind it is about be prepared
for resilience
you can never really call what is going
to be the outcome of extreme events
absolutely and i guess business as usual
uh the definition itself has changed
uh as we look at things today right uh
thank you thank you very much for all
your comments i'll i'll go around with
the set of questions that
we have and uh i do apologize in advance
in case
we can't cover everybody giving the
given the situation given the
time limit but uh if you again had
requested to please keep your comments
uh short so that everybody has a chance
to to answer some of the questions that
we have
because we have some really interesting
conversation pointers
going forward so uh coming back to you
mr shah
i think uh the the main question on the
table really i think we heard that theme
for what everybody spoke
is the whole whole digitization right
whether it is digitization
in terms of what the customer is doing
or the internal digitization
in terms of the way things have changed
in the way we
conduct business at a regular uh you
know
in normal times uh
i would just like to hear your views on
how we as an industry when i say we as
an industry the bfsi
industry is leveraging the digital
opportunity
and is there something we are missing
out or something that we are behind
on uh that you would love to see you
would love to see
uh going forward uh
that's that's i think one of the main
things that we have
experienced through this pandemic is
this wave of digitization
and what i'd like to say right up front
is if you look at the technology
that there is today and the technology
at the start of the pandemic there has
not been
revolutionary change in the technology
the technology was there in the case of
nabil bank
in nepal we had all these digital
solutions out there in the market
but the uptake was very limited from the
customers they would prefer to come to
the brand sit down have a cup of tea
talk to the branch manager
you know discuss their loan repayment so
on and so forth no matter how many times
we said use the app use this use that
you know the uptake was very limited uh
on part of the customer
the pandemic has been a huge um boon in
that you know
in nepal we used to be always given the
example by our
donor agencies and international
agencies of impersona in kenya
to say look at empires in kenya every
kenya even kenyan uses mpisa and how
come you don't have an app like this
you should get apps like this in nepal
and so on and so forth we did a bit of
deep dive into empire saturday what is
this revolutionary app that the kenyans
are using
and we found it had nothing to do with
the app the crime rate is so high in
kenya that people don't want to carry
money
by using mpisa they by not carrying
money the chance of them getting robbed
was far less so they were using
empisa so for us it wasn't crime it was
corona that that moved the customer base
into into digitization
now for the challenge for us is now that
they've gotten used to it they're not
asking let's open a branch near in my
village or in my town or anything
they're saying get me more services that
i can do
i want to open my accounts through
digitization you i want ekyc
i don't want to ever come to the branch
again because you know there could be
all sorts of
things that are happening here and even
when they come to the branch now we've
just introduced an um
branch banking by appointment so they
can take an appointment and actually
come and tell
exactly what they want whether they
should be they're all a deposit and they
don't have to wait in queue and they go
straight through and
get their transactions done so
digitization
has done a quantum leap not because the
technology has
changed but again it comes with the
mindset internally also you know we used
to do processes
a lot of it was paperwork so on and so
forth but now we're moving internally as
well to see how much can we do digitally
because
the work environment has changed we're
all working from home we're working from
you know wherever we are we don't want
people to come to the office and then
you know sort of um contaminate
everybody else as well
so the process of working internally has
changed to be
much more digital the the products that
we had the uptake is much more and now
the challenge is for us
i think as you said the final part of
your question is to find right
partnerships
uh at least in our case we are not
trying to develop everything ourselves
we are not a tech company we are a bank
we have good fintech companies good
uh young entrepreneurs we've got
different products let's see how we can
dovetail those in
with the type of services that we are
doing for instance uh what i said the
appointment banking the qr
at that uh counter so that they can just
tap and do that the
em green pins for the atms all these are
you know vendors uh that are providing
us this uh small fintechs medium big
fintechs that are providing this
and now the challenge is to find the
right fintech partners to sort of
dovetail their products
with the services that our customers
want the the one huge hurdle
of the customer mindset has been
overcome internally also this hurdle of
having to do everything on paperwork and
getting many signatures that has been
overcome
now the challenge for us is to find the
right solutions to be able to deliver
those services
to our customers internal and external
for process changes as well as product
delivery
thank you thank you thank you that was
again uh i think
the whole make versus by conversation
and you know the very important point of
saying technology never really changed
it is us who changed
uh our customers changed uh suddenly you
know the
same plane was able to fly a longer
distance and probably carry more people
and that happened just because
of the fact that uh the way we did
things changed uh
so i think that's a good segment to the
next part of the conversation that we'd
like to have which is on technology
right
so miss honda if this is really a
question for you
in especially looking at the size of sbi
the number of customers and you said
it very rightly uh crisis or no crisis
uh the bank had to continue or all banks
had to earn banks and bfcs have to
continue
to service the customer right it's
probably
brought a lot of things into perspective
for each one of us
uh and i say this whether it's both
professionally as well as personally
uh on technologies that are
really innovative that have changed uh
and are really future ready what are
your
sort of top few things that you would
evaluate or that you look at today
differently
uh when you invest in a technology or
you look at a technology roadmap
in terms of truly making a technology
resilient
and making it future ready and where
should the money really be spent
uh that's the question that i had for
you
okay thank you nimilita
first i think your earlier question i
was really uh it made me
ponder you said uh that banks have they
done enough
have they made the best of the
opportunities and second where are
what are those elements which still need
some more pusher
which are lagging behind i'll quickly uh
you know tell my thoughts on
uh this and then i'll come to what i
look for in the platform when i
uh you know i acquire it and when i want
to go ahead with my
uh future readiness so okay
the first thing is banking industry i
think zeal of banking industry can be
considered as the
third driver for digitalization in our
country
we can say internet and penetration the
first
mobile penetration the second and third
is zero the banking industry
the range of products online products
banking industry has offered
to the customers i think uh it
it is an example and a bank like state
bank of india
i can say that despite 24 000 branches
all across the country and in 32
countries
then we have 93 of the transactions
through non-branch channels so that is
the extent of for digitalization uh
which has happened
so and over and above that the
mobile-based solutions the banking
industry has given
that is absolutely you know people are
zapped by this that
for every need we have a mobile app or a
mobile optimized uh
portal that's what people have been
saying so we have uh
banks have leveraged on the mobile
revolution also
then you said where which elements uh we
they are slightly left behind though sbi
can't afford to leave them behind
what i'm going to talk but then in the
ecosystem probably some more
effort is required see we are having 500
million
uh smart mobiles the subscribers in the
country
but people forget that there are 350
million
feature phone subscribers also so i've
seen
banks you know in sbi we have all kinds
of segments
of customers so we cannot forget any uh
you know whether
it is uh profit making or loss making or
it is not breaking even no we have to
serve that segment of customer also
so this feature from
our customers we have this sbi quick for
example which
sms banking or a missed call banking so
now this has to be launched
by uh all the ecosystem players that's
what my feeling is
second uh aspect where enough has not
been done
is for the check issuing corporate
silencing
see we not only have to take the society
to a less cash society we have to take
it to a less check society also
still we have corporates who issue
paper-based checks where
there is risk also there are products
also because either they say that they
say
no there are not enough number of
products for us of the
user-friendly products for corporates or
secondly maybe the
products are there but their knowledge
transfer has not happened to the extent
it should happen so there also i say our
you know business the way it has
exponentially grown during this pandemic
times
i mean it has to be seen to be believed
the graph which comes to me daily how
the usage has been going up so this is
one opportunity luckily sbi has started
up in time and
pandemic has helped us in uh you know
growing our customer base on
sbi quick uh that sms banking as well as
on
corporate so these two are other things
then you mentioned about
what i look for now many new products
are being launched because
crisis has uh has given us an
opportunity to look at
the what are the new demands like
contactless
payments simple even if somebody is
withdrawing cash from atm
he says no atm have to uh you know touch
five times
no no i don't want to do that can it be
reduced to two touches can it be reduced
to one that's something like
so these kind of new demands have come
and then we look at
spindex we look at platforms so my first
requirement as state bank will be
it has to be robust it has to be ai
enabled
it has to be mobile friendly then it has
to
be scalable yes you know the
very basic thing for sbi it has to be uh
scalable
so these things then ah i should be able
to it should be agile enough that
whatever platform i require for these
new services it has to be agile enough
to
you know later keep on adding new
services that our customers because
customer demands
they'll keep on evolving today there is
one pandemic tomorrow
our customer is evolving and he has new
requirements so he his
infrastructure or his uh technology has
been upgraded so that's why i'll say
these five basic requirements i look for
uh in a platform uh that when i
acquire it
totally totally totally i think uh
scalability is key
um you know being on 24x7
is not just good enough now it should
also be scalable
at all times and i think the point on
feature phones is
super well taken i think uh somewhere or
the other you know in this whole
melee of saying digitization and things
like that we sort of forget that that
segment of
our customers who probably don't have
access and how do we solve for them
that's probably a big challenge and a
bigger challenge to solve
all right well thank you so much for
your views
mr jabun nathan i uh jumped to you in
terms of you know
a good place for us to talk about the
rise of
fintechs insure techs all of these and i
think this
we heard that theme also coming along
uh how how is the industry leveraging
the fintechs in shortex who are probably
being
very nimble in bringing out solutions
who have had solutions in the past that
they're looking at
and what are the different use cases
that that
you all are looking at solving and the
types of partnerships that you are
looking at
with fintechs and in short ranks
in a way if i have to relate to what
kind of syntax and issue
insure text add most value to us it's
worthwhile looking at the value chain
that we are looking at in our entire
delivery from start to finish
the start of it is what how we engage
our distributor
and help them do more in the same time
with their customers
any kind of technology therefore which
helps the distributor
get a better understanding of his
customer
gives him a better ability to engage
either face to face or remotely and take
that through to a logical conclusion of
a buying decision
is one very significant area the second
step
in the value chain is once a distributor
has completed his prospecting
there is a risk assessment and
onboarding which has to happen
this is an area where there are a lot of
interesting use cases
with respect to ecosystems be it in the
context of
know your customer related documentation
or even in the context of risk
assessment
whether it is life health income
that's an area where i would believe
that fintechs can actually
find a significant amount of use cases
the third part of the value chain is
delivery of service to customers
in that area it is really about how well
we can make our own service delivery
architecture
react respond and seamlessly deliver to
the expectations of the customer
keeping in mind that expectations
dramatically change over time
keeping in mind that a customer who
sought a physical
interaction yesterday who moved on to
maybe a digital interaction today
might very well say tomorrow that
everything has to be based on voice
using information that we have available
through various past servicing
interactions with customers
using information that we have from the
ecosystem
using analytics to bind all of this to
an intelligent
service delivery becomes the next
important milestone
last but not the least in the life
insurance business and this is something
that we as a company believe very
strongly in
claims is the ultimate moment of truth
the ability therefore to deliver a claim
process in minutes will become
a key differentiator but this is
sometimes
easier said than done because as old as
insurances insurance fraud is also just
as old
and therefore risk analytics in the
context of fraud
claims the entire ecosystem that
operates in claims
will become another very very
significant area where technology
data analytics can play a very very
significant role for us
so those to my mind would be in a
simplistic sense
the platforms that can tremendously add
value to an insurance organization
thank you when i again you raise a very
very uh pertinent
point and that was probably the next
area that i was going to jump into
and you probably raised two two big
areas of conversation one is on the data
and analytics side
and the application of data and
analytics and the other is the early on
the risk
side so mr savvy i'll i'll jump to you
uh
on the risks right uh the new world the
work from home
uh the new type
uh what are the kind of risks that have
come about
in the industry what are the things what
are the trends that you are seeing
hearing what is
uh what are the kind of problems that
you all are solving
uh as we look at risks that emerge
uh either existing risks that already
existed which we have to
continue to take care of and the new
risks that have emerged
in this new world yes you correctly said
so
when you talk about a technology
technology is being equally used by
good and bad players a potent example
being a ransomware you know so if you
see whenever you are bringing up any
technologies that bring up its own demon
also
the cyber threats are becoming more
sophisticated and it's not a matter of
if
but when you will be faced with such an
attacks so the
recent attacks if you see on global
companies like mercs
shipping giant have cost billions of in
loss of revenues
and you can leave ongoing negative
effects like damage reputations
or lack of shareholder confidence and so
on and so forth
so attacks are virtually non-stop
and you know when we talk about a
protection the
prevention there are a number of ways
how i can
protect myself from any cyber attacks
prevention is a very common
methodologies
but when you talk about prevention it is
not always hundred percent
so if somebody speak in how i can
protect myself
so that is a big question so uh too
often we see organizations are focused
on
guarding against very specific type of
cyber attacks or cyber actors
you know this narrows is the focus is
put on the risk
it's important to understand that cyber
attacks
take many forms you know uh and the
attackers may have
variety of motivations techniques and
even platform from which
uh these attacks can be launched one of
the most difficult type of cyber attacks
to defend against uh the one
launched by the insiders you know i mean
either knowingly
or maybe unknowingly but they tend to
have
physical access full knowledge of the
infrastructure and many even have
benefited from privileges giving to
more access and more damage that they
can do
so uh ransomware or
bad actors have learned that they have a
better chance of achieving their goal
by getting more money out of it
if they destroy the backup completely
because backup is something which
any organization has an immediate
measure of
their protection right in case there's
attack how i can recover is a backup
and this actually has placed a backup
under the direct attack
so people still believe that i have a
backup so i am safe but many of the
times it has happened that
uh sony is a big example of this that
when they go and check out the backup
itself was attacked by a cyber attack
and there was absolutely nothing that
they can do
and if you see the backup admins are the
main target
for compromise through variety of attack
vectors because their access is trusted
and they can easily and rapidly become
an effective change
and to carry out these attacks and if
you see most of the organization
backups are from the security angle are
the most neglected nobody look at the
backup to be secured
and its time has come that we one has to
focus on how they can secure their
backups
also because if we talk about prevention
there are a lot many things that
people are talking about ranging from
firewall to aps ips
uh three prevention so on and so forth
but what if
even if somebody enters in so look at
your file systems
okay or whatever data that you hold on
clouds even that can be deleted
so uh yeah finally is what the cloud is
not a inherently secured location for
backup it's just
different from what product environment
you have
so uh even i mean there is a
misconception that
though madam has clearly stated the
disaster recovery does not equal to
cyber recovery
you have a disaster recovery does not
mean that you can recover from it
it is prone to cyber attacks so the good
cyber recovery strategy
takes all of these into account so since
i
uh we partnered with dell emc so dell
emc has a cyber residency solutions and
services
including their protect cyber recovery
which provides a solution which
if you heard about a air gap technology
wherein your data
the backup data has been isolated from
your existing network
using these technologies and whenever
there is a new change in data which is
coming in
using an ai artificial intelligence it
can actually cross
check is the data is being modified to
an extent which is
beyond normal that means suppose any
increment or any applications usually
hardly changes a day the changes should
be one or two percent
but certainly if i found a change more
than that or
uh the files which usually are not
touched upon
has been touched abnormally then i can
alert
so that instead of opening my repository
of backup
i will copy it into the secondary
location called as a sandboxing and i
can check it out
so these are the things which actually
helps customers so the modern
and a powerful cyber residency strategy
from dell emc
uh protections are key of enabling
customer to
increase their business agility uh and
i and i i think that uh when we when we
talk about digitalization
i mean security is a most important part
and one should
look for it and we as a partner are not
only into technologies
providing the technologies which can
help in terms of uh
building a private cloud or moving
people to move into the public cloud
but also into making sure that how the
data which has been protected will be
secured
from these actors
thank you sure sure thank you i think
thank you i think that's
that's very well said and i think that's
very well accepted as well and i think
um it's important for all of us to think
of all aspects of this
security cyber attack all of those kind
of things and
probably more so even now right
so mr nike i'll quickly jump to you in
terms of
you know with with increasing
digitization and night
mr jamal talked about you know the
increasing amount of data that
is coming along the amount of he
alluded to voice analytics which is
again probably become
a big thing that we're talking about
about
data that we probably had or have or
collect in the
through the course of our customer
journeys but we don't probably
use them very well uh and also
this whole thing of embedding analytics
for
us to make uh data-driven decisions
and use analytics to make business
decisions
easier all of those kind of things uh
what do you feel has changed
uh have you seen a change in mindset
have you seen a change in adoption
uh on the analytics data
data area within the organization uh
and you know some of the nuggets in that
area would be very helpful
for the audience
yeah i think uh along with uh
talking change in mindset regarding
digitization mindset regarding adoption
of
a lot of analytics based techniques also
has
uh undergone a significant change uh
we had been uh using aiml solutions
it's only uh now that it's so
most of our solutions are developed by
our business intelligence units where we
have
data developing now
not only are the data scientists
developing but right as we speak we are
running a training program for
underwriters to learn
uh programming language like python so
they would uh
participate along with the data
scientists in
working on these solutions so the
mindset changes there and
and it is something that is happening
across the organization
you speak it's not only not technology
obviously not just a realm of just the
technology department it's the business
which drives the technology in most of
the cases
we know that in digitization but in
something as
complex as aiml we have seen other parts
of the organization also wanting to
learn wanting to
understand and participate in the
co-creation of solutions and we have
created solutions
along the way which have kind of
significantly eased
uh policy servicing if i may
uh quote a couple of examples uh we had
we have put in place solution for uh
medical claims authorization which is
based on
uh it uses of ai as well as
ml techniques this is when you go to
hospital and
want to apply for cashless claim usually
the process takes about a couple of
hours where
you put in doctor's diagnosis you send
and give all that to the tpa desk out
there
along with your policy details and then
it's sent back to the insurer and should
have processed that and sends it back
that okay you can get it and we'll pay
whatever
is the amount that is there now here we
are
digitizing this completely and then
using ai to process
the information that is there and a lot
of the information is
completely free doctor's diagnosis in
complete pre-test so the ai reads that
it figures out
from the policy terms and conditions
whether the case is medically admissible
or not so that's
that's eliminating what a doctor does in
the back end and once that
diagnosis is done whether
[Music]
the ai determines that it is medically
admissible then there's ml solution
which actually
decides what's the amount that can be
approved this whole process takes place
in
less than 90 seconds so that
significantly i mean this is a complete
change in the way
uh the whole process occurs and uh of
the uh
right now we are doing about for a
corporate uh cashless gate about 70
of our uh entire uh authorizations are
being done through this aiml process so
it's a significant change from the
earlier process which you take
uh uh one and after two hours for uh
getting that authorization and
especially a time need when you're
wanting to get yourself admitted to a
hospital
you want the least amount of friction
out there uh a similar case in
um with policy renewals are for labs
motor policies right
so if your policy lapses you kind of
need to uh
get a survey done to see whether there's
any damage in the lab spirit before you
uh
policy is the issue so and usually when
you realize that your policy has lapsed
it's already
uh you'll realize sometime in
middle of night or something and then
you kind of wait for
uh putting in your request then someone
will send a
surveyor that could any time between 24
to 72 hours per survey to reach you
depending on your availability surveys
availability
so now we have a solution where the
customer can just take
via photos from his app and uh there's a
stencil given of the vehicle so he has
to take photos in those eight
uh locations and there's a air solution
which
reads the images and figures out whether
there is any damage or
dent on the car and if there's no damage
it just passes this completely and the
policy is issued instantaneously so it
completely removes the friction from the
process again
using ai solutions and
uh customer can do this 24x7 it doesn't
have to wait for
the survey to be available and survey to
reach you at place so
there are and these are solutions that
now
the claims and underwriting team are
building along with the
data scientists it's not just the data
scientists who are
working on this it's the entire
organization
is coming together and working on these
solutions and then many more of these
which we are
kind of putting in place but uh the
the mindset change has been that earlier
what used to be a preserve just the
technology or the
uh data scientist team now it's more uh
entire organization which is
working on it working in agile teams and
they are working on the development
with using agile methodologies and
that's the mindset change that
i see that has come about that's that's
absolutely fantastic it's almost like a
science fiction movie coming to life
really
we listen to you know the way the way
things are changing
uh mr gerwald i'll jump to you in terms
of
all of these changes happening right the
technology backbone
uh has sort of become so so important
uh imagine if the person was trying to
take a picture
in in the in the case of trying to
at a hospital and the technology didn't
work or the technology gave inaccuracies
and things like that right so
really the backbone of running all of
this is the technology it's important
for the technology to be always
available
how have technology teams scaled up how
have technology
seems more uh and what are the key
changes you're seeing in the
tech world especially from a people
a skill standpoint
yeah so i think technology world has
been changing i think technology and
financial services has been a little bit
behind but
if you look at the technology world the
emergence of
you know server executing or cloud
computing these are not new phenomena
i mean they have been associated with
lot of digital transformation
but a lot of these phenomenas are you
know more than a decade old
uh now and they have we have built we
have seen large platforms coming out of
this
phenomenons you know whether you talk
about amazon globally or
ali or google or facebook these are all
uh
you know in that sense kind of a decade
old phenomenons
i think in the enterprise context what
we have seen is a
is a differentiation in terms of what
how enterprises look at their
you know key role in terms of uh
managing technology and what kind of
technology they are adopting
i can go area by area so for example
today uh you know earlier
you know everybody was running large
data center and i'm sure miss honda
still runs
huge amount of data centers probably
they are the largest consumer of data
center services
in the country today but we are also
seeing emergence of
iis solutions past solutions uh sas
solutions
machine learning as a service so i think
the whole areas in terms of
infrastructure management and then
capability to
manage and orchestrate those services i
think that is a new capability
which enterprises are more and more
attuning to how do they architect the
systems on
on these new capabilities to leverage
these capabilities
and where to leverage i think those are
the new i would say engineering
capabilities when you look at security
um i think our panelists talked about
security
uh you know we've seen perimeter
security where we would prevent our door
very
artfully and now there's no perimeter
which exists the moment we go into a
multi-cloud and hybrid cloud security
there is no perimeter the world is your
perimeter
right and and now the data is
transmitted via satellite so beyond
earth as well
so your perimeter is everywhere right in
that sense
so how do you orchestrate security so
there are new principles of security was
emerging there are new skill set on
security which is emerging
not only security now you have auto
remediation technologies
uh both on infrastructure side both
security side so i think the skill set
are getting more and more specialized on
each of the technology areas
um you know one thing i've always talked
about you know when we look at
enterprise company or say financial
services company because personal people
are international
we will have multiple you know units of
financial services
there will be asset department there
will be liability department and so on
so forth and then there will be one
technology department
and this cycle completely gets reversed
when you go to technology company they
will have a devops department they would
have
application department and they would
have an engineering data engineering
department
and there will be one finance department
right so i think this
merger is happening where we are seeing
that
more specialized area and skills are
what is required in technology
we are also seeing that a lot of these
technology adoptions
um there are people who have taken a lot
of
insourcing approach from a complete a
vendor or managed service
provider approach that collaboration is
is much higher
in terms of skill set and every
uh you know every day we are seeing a
launch of a new company
a new method of either doing a log
analytics either doing a machine
learning either doing a data storage
so i think that skill set is becoming
more and more specialized rather than a
generic skill set
and we are seeing that emerging areas
across the board and i can talk
you know 10 different areas from
application development to devops
girish talked about you know agile
development
we talked about hybrid cloud we talked
about security
and the skill sets will become more and
more specialized and the skill set to
orchestrate these multiple plethora of
services
i think is getting more and more complex
while it simplifies the management
but the skill sets are getting more
complex and that's the emergence and
that's the effort i think everybody is
taking the technology skill sets
are being transmitted to the business as
girish rightly pointed out
um you know who who thought about you
know
that you would have underwriters or
business people learning programming
but that's the truth today um so i think
it it's just becoming a common
place i mean we see enough ads on the
internet where seven year
old kids are learning how to program
right everybody wants to teach their
kids the programming language
uh i'm sure there'll be a time that you
know
sometime in the future kids will learn
programming language before speaking
language
so who knows what will happen
yes anyway uh i had i had just have a
minute
more and i did have a question for mr
lee which was very linked to this in
terms of how are you attracting talent
mr lee we just have a minute i'm
sorry about this how are you attracting
and retaining talent
uh in this ever-changing world and you
know going forward
probably at 12 45 right now for the
talent
of intention uh in hong kong and china
because we are lucky we have a bunch of
supply
from the very famous university
particularly in greater china region
taiwan hong kong mainland china
even some good candidates from india
pakistan so okay uh the key things
is uh we keep uh the disruptive
technology really help
to solving the technology problem uh the
business problem this is the first thing
the second thing is is we keep our our
id
industry all the time is interesting
interesting is the most important things
because
you know uh we focus on business uh how
to solve the problem
for the business but uh go to china
uh in the last uh three years
we drive the hacker from something uh
some uh
so uh i.t society did we encouraging
on the funny and interesting topic let
the young people to do the research help
the government
help the society so uh how to combine
with this kind of
morale and then how to contribute their
know-how
transformed into a intelligence to help
our industries
the most important things so um
my idea is that we are trying to keep uh
the talent
we are all the time enjoying their
environment this is my my two cents yeah
thank you thank you so much then thank
you everybody for for
an extremely engaging panel uh i thank
you on behalf of
all of us for for making this such an
interesting discussion
thanks kavya and back to you